Blades, Rubén. Rubén Blades recordings and papers: Guide AWM Spec Coll 100
Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library
Rubén Blades recordings and papers
1948-2015
Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library
AWM Spec Coll 100
29.5 linear feet
Commercial and privately produced sound and audiovisual recordings; periodicals; books; promotional materials, photographs, posters, correspondence, professional and business documents, scripts, ephemera and realia documenting the career of Rubén Blades, musician, actor and political figure from Panama.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The first contents of the collection were given to the Harvard Music Library, Archive of World Music in August 2008 by Alison Weinstock. In the summer of 2014, a larger group of materials was donated by Blades himself, consisting of personal papers, correspondence and additional periodical and press coverage. Additional acquisitions are anticipated in the future.
Conditions Governing Access
As of 2015, one box of materials (Series XIV, Box 6) is restricted from public access due to containing personal and financial information. There are no restrictions on physical access for the remainder of the collection. A very small amount of material is restricted until after the death of the artist. Because much of this material is under copyright, the permission of the copyright holder is required before reproductions can be made. All requests for access should be forwarded to the curatorial staff of the Archive of World Music.
Biographical and Historical Note
Rubén Blades Bellido de Luna was born in Panama City, Panama on July 16, 1948. He is an internationally prominent and popular musician, actor and politician. His musical career as a singer and composer of Latin popular music styles has won him many accolades, including multiple Grammy and Latin Grammy awards. He played a key role in the salsa music scene in New York in the 1970s.
In addition to being an accomplished musician, Blades is also a lawyer. He studied law at the Universidad de Panama in the early 1970s and he later graduated in 1985 with a Master's degree in International Law from Harvard University Law School. Social, cultural and political concerns have played a major part in Blades' life and music. In recent years, Blades served a term as Minister of Tourism in Panama from 2004 to 2009.
As an actor, Blades has performed in many commercial films, including Crossover Dreams (1985) and Once Upon a Time in Mexico (2003).
As a well-known figure, many resources about Blades' life and career are widely available. This biographical sketch is necessarily brief and focused on materials currently available in the collection.
Scope and Content Note
When first acquired in 2008, the collection was comprised of materials assembled by Alison Weinstock, a resident of the Boston area who maintains a website dedicated to the work of Rubén Blades. Since then Weinstock has forwarded additional materials acquired from Blades' friends in the music industry, as well as from Paula Campbell, Blades' girlfriend in the 1970s (the song Paula C was written about her). Weinstock has also purchased many other items at auction that have become part of the collection. In the summer of 2014, a much larger cache of materials was donated by Blades himself. Included in this donation were professional and personal documents that span the entire range of Blades' career as a singer, actor, politician and activist. Further donations are expected in the future.
The predominant musical genre represented in the collection is salsa, a Latin dance music style incorporating traditional and popular song forms that originate from countries such as Puerto Rico, Cuba, the Dominican Republic, Panama and the United States. Elements of jazz and rock are also frequently included in salsa music. Blades' musical career is distinguished by his many collaborations with musicians across genres, including his work in musical theater forms. He is also known for incorporating sociocultural and political commentary within salsa and Latin popular music.
The collection includes ephemera, newspaper clippings, correspondence and campaign materials relating to Blades' bid for the office of President of Panama in 1994. In that run he founded and became candidate of the political party known as the Papa Egoró Movement. ["Papa Egoró" translates as "Mother Earth" in the language of the indigenous Embera people of Panama and Colombia, and the English version of the party name is "Mother Earth Movement"; in Spanish, it is called the MPE, or "Movimiento Papa Egoró."].
The collection contains many periodical articles from the Latin American and United States press covering Blades' own music and popular Latin music in general. Also included are privately produced recordings, most of which are live concerts, television broadcasts and interviews. Commercially published sound recordings (LPs and CDs) and books in the collection have been individually cataloged and are not listed in this finding aid. These may be found by searching the Hollis catalog with "Rubén Blades Archives."
Blades' varied activities provide a wealth of material for a range of research topics. His professional documents (including contracts and business manuscripts) provide a window into the salsa and popular music industries of the 1980s-2000s. His acting documents and scripts show connections between music and film industries during that same period, while a collection of fan mail traces his reception in popular culture. His political documents and correspondence provide insight into Latin American political history, particularly in Panama during the 1990s. His extensive collection of handwritten lyrics offer a glimpse into the creative process of a giant of salsa history.
Note to Users: For the purpose of this finding aid, subject and index terms and proper names have been standardized according to the OCLC authority file, when found.
Arrangement
Series I. Unpublished audio and audiovisual recordings, 1968-2010 (6 boxes)
___Subseries 1. Audio recordings on CD and cassette
___Subseries 2. Promotional audio recordings
___Subseries 3. Audiovisual recordings on DVD
___Subseries 4. Audiovisual recordings on videocassette
Series II. Periodicals, 1964-2011 (5 boxes)
Series III. Publicity, promotional materials and programs, 1985-2014 (2 boxes)
___Subseries 1. Press kits
___Subseries 2. Programs
___Subseries 3. Miscellaneous
Series IV. Political materials, 1975-2010 (3 boxes)
___Subseries 1. Papa Egoró Movement
___Subseries 2. Correspondence and other political documents
___Subseries 3. Blades political clippings
___Subseries 4. General political clippings
Series V. Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1977-2013 (4 boxes)
Series VI. Correspondence, 1976 - 2012 (3 boxes)
___Subseries 1. General correspondence
___Subseries 2. Fan mail
___Subseries 3. Greeting cards
___Subseries 4. Miscellaneous
___Subseries 5. Correspondence donated by Paula Campbell from 1978
Series VII. Photographs, 1971-1994 (2 boxes)
Series VIII. Posters, 1988-2010 (1 box)
Series IX. Realia (2 boxes)
Series X. General documents and manuscripts, 1973-2002 (4 boxes)
___Subseries 1. Professional documents
___Subseries 2. Hobbies, calendars and personal purchases
___Subseries 3. Chinese newspapers
___Subseries 4. Writings about Rubén Blades
Series XI. Music and lyrics (2 boxes)
Series XII. Acting documents, 1987-2013 (2 boxes)
___Subseries 1. General acting files
___Subseries 2. Materials relating to The Capeman
Series XIII. Scripts and production notes, 1983-2012 (4 boxes)
Series XIV. Business and financial documents, 1970s-2000s (5 boxes)
___Subseries 1. Business correspondence
___Subseries 2. Contracts and negotiations
___Subseries 3. Legal documents
___Subseries 4. Royalty statements
___Subseries 5. Financial documents
New York (N.Y.); New York; Panama; Música tropical; Salsa (Music); Latin jazz; Singers - Panama; Music-United States-New York; Popular music -- Latin America; Popular music - United States; Political campaigns - Panama; Actors - United States; Clippings; Ephemera (general object genre); Interviews; Motion pictures; Musical theater; Photographs; Radio broadcasts; Sound recordings; Television broadcasts; Videocassettes; Correspondence; Business Documents; Fan Mail; Scripts; Periodicals
- Series I. Audio and audiovisual recordings, 1968-2010; 6 boxes; 6 boxes.
  - Subseries 1. Audio recordings on CD and cassette, Box 1.
    General
    The recordings here are privately produced on CD-R and are presented chronologically.
    - Rubén Blades and Cheo Feliciano in Puerto Rico, live concert, 1 CD-Rs
    - Los Salvajes de Ritmo and Rubén Blades, A las Seis, mp3 files, 1968; 1 CD-Rs
    - Various singles from Panama, and two songs from Francisco "Bush" Buckley, mp3 files, 1968; 1 CD-Rs
    - Para Rubén Blades, Jr. de Bush, conversational tape recorded by Francisco "Bush" Buckley and friends that was sent to Blades in New York City., 1975; 1 analog audio cassette.
    - Para Rubén Blades, Jr. de Bush, conversational tape recorded by Francisco "Bush" Buckley and friends, that was sent to Blades in New York City, data files, made from original analog audio cassette, 1975; 1 CD-Rs
    - Willie Colón and Rubén Blades in Peru, live concert, 1978; 1 CD-Rs
    - Amnesty International, Live in New Jersey, broadcast on WNEW, various artists; Rubén Blades: Muévete, Sun City., 1986-6-15; 5 CD-Rs
    - Homeless Children's Medical Benefit, live, Paul Simonand Friends (Rubén Blades, backup on Teenager in Love), 1987-12-13; 2 CD-Rs
    - Rubén Blades with Son del Solar, and Willie Colón, live concert, Hiram Bithorn Stadium, San Juan, Puerto Rico, 1993; 1 CD-Rs
    - Rubén Blades with Son del Solar, live concert, Maracaibo Stadium, Venezuela, 1994; 1 CD-Rs
    - A Latino Response to Cultural Cleansing, the keynote address by Rubén Blades at the National Association of Latino Arts and Culture Conference, San Antonio, Texas, Recorded by Alternative Radio, 1995-9-28; 1 audiocassettes
    - Rubén Blades with Son del Solar, Jimmy Bosch - guest Marc Anthony, Seattle, WA, live concert, 1996; 4 CD-Rs
    - Live at Carnegie Hall, audience recording, 1997; 1 CD-Rs
    - Willie Colón and Rubén Carlota (Venezuela), live concert, 1998; 1 CD-Rs
    - Live at Northeastern University, Boston, MA, with Editus, 2000; 2 CD-Rs
    - Caracas Pop Festival, guest song with Maná, live concert, 2001-1-19; 2 CD-Rs
    - Apollo Theater, live concert, guest: Jimmy Bosch, 9 songs, 2001-6-22; 1 CD-Rs
    - Live in Baltimore, MD, outdoor concert; plus additional songs, 2001-7-15; 2 CD-Rs
    - Live in Veracruz, Mexico, mp3 files, 2001; 1 CD-Rs
    - Caracas Pop Festival, live concert, guest song, January 2002; 2 CD-Rs
    - Live at the Museo de la Nación, Lima, Peru, with Editus, 2003-10-17; 2 CD-Rs
    - Salsa America radio program from WDNA in Miami, FL, hosted by Larry Harlow, 2010-9-15-2010-10-15; 5 CD-Rs
    - Live in the Dominican Republic, 10 songs., 2000s; 1 CD-Rs
    - Tape dub made by Blades: "Eddy Martin; Nine Songs"
  - Subseries 2. Promotional audio recordings, Box 1.
    The recordings here are sample promotional recordings produced by ASR Recording Services, Inc. in Fairfield, NJ
    - Sample 8-track audio tape cartridge, "Not for Resale" from ASR Recording Services, marked FANIA 8XT SLP 00500 [handwritten]
    - Sample audio cassette tape, "Not for Resale" from ASR Recording Services, marked FANIA VS-42 [typed]
  - Subseries 3. Audiovisual recordings on DVD, Boxes 2-4.
    The recordings here are privately produced on DVD-R and are presented chronologically.
    Note: Many of the DVD-Rs are digital copies of the videocassettes listed below.
    - Conversando con Rubén Blades: Hace 20 Años, interviewed by Dr. Luis Delgado-Aparicio Porta, Canal 9 television, Peru; interviews and musical segments, includes appearance by Mario Vargas Llosa, 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Los Salvajes del Ritmo, Francisco "Bush" Buckley and su Nuevo Sonido, broadcast from Panama television; old clips and more recent interview clips, 1970s; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades, Willie Colón and Hector Lavoe, 1970s; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Videos from the 70s; Caracas Pop Festival, press conference with the Fundación Ozzie Guillén; musical excerpts from Esencia Latina; Rubén Blades and Franco de Vita on El Show de Carolina Gómez-Ávila, Venezuelan television, 1970s; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades, Willie Colón and Tito Puente, live in Venezuela, 45 min, 1979; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Fania All Stars, live in Venezuela, Rubén Blades sings La Palabra Adios, 1981; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Fania All Stars, live in Panama, 1981; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Fania All Stars, live in Cannes, 1981; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Conversando with Dr. Luis Delgado-Aparicio Porta, interview and performances from various television sources, 1983; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades on Puerto Rico television, 1984; 1992; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades appearance on the David Letterman Show (excerpt); performs an early version of The Hit, Quicktime file, 1985; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades appearance on The Tonight Show (complete); performs the song Cuentas del Alma from the album Escenas, 1985-11-22; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades on the 28th Grammy award show, 1986; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Festival de la Salsa Winston, Puerto Rico television special on Rubén Blades, 1984; 1986; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades and Seis del Solar, 1984; 1986; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Excerpts from Grammy Awards; Rubén Blades, Lou Reed, Buster Poindexter (David Johansen), 1988; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Festival de la Salsa Winston, Puerto Rico television special on Rubén Blades, 1988; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades on the 31st and 29th Grammy Awards, 1989; 1987; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades in Washington DC, live outdoor concert, 6 songs, plus additional material, 1990; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Especial de Rubén Blades en Puerto Rico, Panama television special, 1990; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Live concert Panama, Rubén Blades with Son del Solar, 1990; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Live concert at El Poliedro, in Caracas, Venezuela, guest: Tite Curet Alonso, 1993; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Exclusiva Venezuela, television special; MTV segments; Papa Egoro footage; and additional material, 1994; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades appearance on The X-Files, in the episode El Mundo Gira, Season 4, 1996.; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Somos un Solo Pueblo, television musical documentary produced by Banco Popular de Puerto Rico, 1996; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Al Compas de un Sentimiento, produced by Banco Popular de Puerto Rico, directed by Marcos Zurinaga, 1996; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Maestra Vida, theater production, directed by Bruce Quinn, in Panama, amateur video, 1997; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Live at Carnegie Hall, 1997; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Willie Colón and Rubén Carlota (Venezuela), live concert, 1998-7-19; 1998; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Press conferences including: Rubén Carlota, Editus, from television, 1998; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - El Sida Y Tú, with Franco DeVita, from television, 1998; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Roll of the Dice: Making of the Capeman, documentary, 1998; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - The Capeman, press video, 1998; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - The Capeman, poor quality audience video, 1998; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Sessions at W. 54th, 1999; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Live concert with Editus, at the Poliedro, 1999; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Discovery en Español episode: Buscando América: La Vida de Rubén Blades, television broadcast; Panama television interview, 1999; 1992; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Patria Entera, Rubén Blades with Editus; guest [on disc 2], Osvaldo Ayala, accordion; Balboa Stadium, Panama City, Panama, live concert on the occasion of the return of the Panama Canal to Panama; disc 3: Bush and sus Magníficos, Bobby Valentin, 1999-12-31; 2000; 3 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Imágenes, Rubén Blades with Ray Barretto Orchestra, New Jersey Public Television; Rubén Blades with Editus, Montreux Jazz Festival, 1975-7-19; 2000; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Interviews, press conferences, in Panama and Venezuela [dvd is damaged], 2001; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - La Rosa de los Vientos presentation, interview, 2001; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades with Editus, live in Baltimore, MD, filmed by Jorge Alegria, 2001-7-15; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades, episode segments of Gideon's Crossing, 2001; 2000; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades with Editus, live in New Haven, CT, filmed by Jorge Alegria, 2002; 3 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades with Editus, live in Panama, 2002; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Bobby Valentin, ¡En Vivo! 35 Aniversario: Vuelve A La Carcel, Penitenciaria Estatal "Oso Blanco" in Rio Piedras, Puerto Rico, live concert, 2002; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - New Year's Eve, live outdoor concert in Panama, television, 2002; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Appearance on television program, Resurrection Boulevard, episode: Vergüenza, 2002; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Interview with Rubén Blades on Panama Telemetro television program, De Mujeres y de Todo; interview in Hollywood on Univision television, 1990; 2002; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Centenario, Independence Day from Colombia, live outdoor concert in Panama, 2003-11-3; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Teleton 20-30, including Rubén Blades and Cheo Feliciano, Panama, December 2003; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades and the Spanish Harlem Orchestra, live concert in Manatí, Puerto Rico, 2004-7-3; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades and the Spanish Harlem Orchestra, live concert at San Sebastian Jazz Festival, 2004-7-25; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Various footage, 2004; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades receives honorary PhD from Berklee College of Music, filmed by Bruce Weinstock, 2005-4-1; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Rubén Blades receives ASCAP Founders Award, 13th Annual El Premio ASCAP Awards, 2005-4-5; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Francisco "Bush" Buckley and su Nuevo Sonido, live at Club Unión, Panama, 2005 or 2006.; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Alison Weinstock visits Panama and interviews friends of Blades, including Francisco "Bush" Buckley, Roberto Cedeño, Rómulo Castro, Luis Arteaga, 2006; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Carnaval de Panama, 2007-2-19; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Carnaval de Panama, Gran Combo, 2007-2-19; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - You Tube videos; Viva la Música, contestants on Blades tribute night, 2008; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Maestra Vida, theater production, directed by Bruce Quinn, at the Teatro en Círculo, Panama City, Panama, One disc contains comments by Blades about writing, before and after the production, 2009-4-29; 3 DVD-Rs (2 copies).
    - Interview with Rubén Blades on SER-TV television program, Gente de Mente, 2009-7-11; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Interview on Panama Telemetro television program, En Exclusiva, Rubén Blades: Maestra Vida, 2009-7-17; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Profile and interview with Rubén Blades on PBS News Hour, 2010-2-10; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Interview with Rubén Blades at the National Museum of American History, Washington, D.C., 2010-3-27; 2 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Live performance of La Raza Latina with Rubén Blades at Lincoln Center's Damrosch Park, 2010-8-14; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Live performance of Rubén Blades with the Roberto Delgado Orchestra at the Festival de Jazz de Vitoria in Gasteiz, Spain, 2011-7-15; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Una noche con Ruben Blades - Encuentro; Interview with Ruben Blades and Edgar Borges, moderated by Ignacio Latasa, upon the release of the digital version of Vinculos, Apuntes con Ruben Blades (donated by Ruben Blades), 2014-6-3; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Expedición 2 Natibo Visa, chapter 3 about Rubén Blades; Sevilla, Sevilla; Puerto Rico and Mexico; as a Grammy presenter; live interviews and press conferences, 2005; 4/20/1992; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Letterman, Cavett; Heart of the Deal, HBO short movie; AIDS television spot; appearance on episode of Politically Incorrect, 1985; 1990; 2000; 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Music segments, 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - El Show de Rubén Blades from Pilot to show number 24, data files., 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
    - Several Venevisión (Venezuelan television) shows: Rubén Blades: Su Música, with Seis del Solar; Papa Egoro special; several other shows, 1 DVDs (DVD-R)
  - Subseries 4. Audiovisual recordings on videocassette, Boxes 5-6.
    The recordings here are privately produced on VHS and are presented chronologically.
    Note: Many of the videocassettes have been digitized on the DVD-Rs above.
    - ABC Gideon's Crossing Hispanic Roles in Hollywood, 2001-03-21
    - Albrook, Panama #1, 1993
    - Albrook, Panama #2, 1993
    - Amnesty International, Chile with Rubén Blades and Sting
    - Ancon 4 Cuñas 30/Ecologia Rubén Blades, 1987-04
    - Ancon: Three spots and documentary
    - Berklee College of Music Graduation
    - Blades Running NBC News [Not for Broadcast], 1993-12-01
    - Buscando America: La Vide de Rubén Blades (entrevista cruda) Betas 1-14
    - "Camaleón" song video
    - "Caminando" song video with Gilberto Santa Rosa
    - "Cantan a Puerto Rico" TV Special, 1991-08
    - Cerveza Panama
    - "Christina en L.A." Panel on Political Artists with Rubén Blades, Esai Moralo, Danny Rivera, and Johnny Ventura
    - City Life Episode 101 "Seeking Community", 1998-05-21
    - City Life Episode 102 "Looking for Love", 1998-05-28
    - City Life Episode 103 "Making It", 1998-06-14
    - Clinton Inauguration video, Rubén Blades introduces segment, 1993; 1 videocassettes
    - "Como Un Huracán" song video
    - Concert at University of Puerto Rico
    - Concert in Puerto Rico with Rubén Blades, Son de Solar, and Willie Colon #2, 1993-02-28
    - Concierto Mayor de los Soneros, 1979-03-30
    - Discovery en Español Biography; television interviews from De Mujeres and de Todo, and El Show de Paul Rodriguez, 2002; 1990; 2001; 1 videocassettes
    - Disney American Teachers Awards
    - Duets, commercial tape Stardust, One More for the Road (Rubén Blades as the bartender in Lou Reed's video), 1988; 1 videocassettes
    - El Sida y Tú
    - EPK Mundo [English version]
    - EPK Mundo [Spanish version]
    - "Eres Mi Canción" song video
    - Eye on LA KABC-TV Grammy Win, 2000-03-18
    - Gideon's Crossing Pilot Episode, 2000-10-10
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 102 "The Way"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 103 "The Race"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 104 "A Routine Case"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 105 "Father Knows Best"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 106 "The Lottery"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 108 "The Mistake"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 109 "Is there a Wise Man in the House?"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 110 "Freak Show"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 111 "Hinkytown"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 116 "Clinical Enigma"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 117 "Dr. Cherry Must Be Stopped"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 118 "Orphans"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 119 "Life Sentences"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 120 "Prodigal Dad"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 121 "The Others"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 122 "Filaments and Ligatures"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 123 "Flashpoint"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 124 "The Crash"
    - Gideon's Crossing Episode 125 "Heart of Glass"
    - Gipsy Kings Tierra Gitana documentary by Nonesuch Records/Atlantic, 1996-07-24
    - Highlights 1, various, [includes the Dick Cavett Show]; AIDS/Condoms, public service spot, with La Rosa (guitar), Panama, 1985; 1997; 1 videocassettes
    - Highlights 2, various, including Sessions at W. 54th, Panama Live, 2002; 1999; 1 videocassettes
    - Hopes On Hold, commercial video single, 1988; 1 videocassettes
    - Identity Video, Hispanic Heritage Awards Foundation (donated by Rubén Blades), 2003; 1 videocassettes
    - Imágenes, with Ray Barretto; Montreux Jazz Fest; 20-30 Teleton, 1975-2003-12-14; 1 videocassettes
    - Images of Race at the Movies (donated by Rubén Blades), 1 videocassettes
    - In a New Light
    - Into the Night Rick Dees Show
    - Lehman College Graduation